okay let's look at the solution for our
data dependencies quiz we have these
four instructions and for each type of
dependence we need to figure out whether
these pairs of instructions have these
dependencies let's start with I 1 2 I 3
we already know that there is no read
after write dependence that is because I
3 doesn't use the R 1 value produced by
the I 1 write after read would mean that
I 3 is writing a result into a register
that was supposed to be read by I 1
which is not true write after write
would mean that I 3 is overwriting the
result produced by I 1 and that is true
now let's go from i1 to i4 i 1 is
producing r1 i for is reading r1 but the
value that i for is supposed to read
here is not the one produced by i1 it is
the value produced by I 3 so in fact
there is no raw dependence from i1 to i4
that would occur only if I four was
reading r1 that was produced by i1 which
is not happening
is there a write after read dependence
is I four overwriting r4 that was
supposed to be read by i1 no because I 1
is not reading r4 finally is there a
write after write dependence no for two
reasons one is that I 4 is writing to a
different register then I 1 so there
cannot be an output dependence another
reason is that even if I four was
writing to r1 that would be an output
dependence between I 3 and I 4 so there
will be an output dependence from i1 to
i3 and then from i3 to i4 but because
the right is happening to our 4 and here
to our 1 certainly there is no write
after write dependence finally let us
look at I 2 2 I 3 is there a read after
write dependence is i2 producing a
register that is read by i3 no it is not
right after read would mean that I 3 is
overwriting
a register that I too needed to read and
that is true because I 2 needs to read
r1 before I 3 overrides it so we have a
right after independence and finally we
do not have a right after right because
they are accessing different registers
for writing so this is again not
selected so the only checkmarks you were
supposed to put in are this one and this
one